Diwakar Kumar

Full Stack Web Developer | Solution Architect | Distinguished Engineer

Phone: +91-9971689261 | Email: diwakar6853@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/DKSingh02 | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/diwakar-kumar-66b87578 | Medium:

@diwakarsingh6853

Professional Summary

Highly accomplished Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of experience in designing, developing, and deploying high-performance web applications...

Skills

Frontend: Angular, React, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap,

jQuery

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, NestJS, RESTful APIs, GraphQL

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB

DevOps: Docker, Jenkins, AWS (EC2, Lambda, SQS, ElastiCache, S3, ECS), Kubernetes,

Terraform, CI/CD Pipelines

Testing: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Protractor, Cypress

Version Control & Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, JIRA, Webpack, Babel, Grunt, Postman,

Swagger, Bruno

Others: System Design, SOLID, ACID, OOP, Performance Optimization, Web Accessibility, DS &

Algorithms, Gen AI, Prompt Engineering, ChatGPT-4, Claude 3.7, RAG, MCP

Professional Experience

Fidelity International | Expert Engineer | April 2022 - Present

- Led the development of an internal systematic investment platform managing equity and

fixed-income portfolios using NX Monorepo architecture.

- Delivered end-to-end product development including requirements gathering, frontend development, RESTful API creation, and deployment.
- Leading the PAS to Kubernetes migration team, providing best-practice guidelines, technical reviews, and strategic planning.
- Technologies: Angular, TypeScript, React, Redux, Ag-Grid, Chart.js, Node.js, NestJS, TypeORM, NX Monorepo, Micro Frontend, RxJS, NgRx, MySQL, AWS Services, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform.

Publicis Sapient | Senior Associate Experience Technology L2 | March 2019 - April 2022

- Client: Verizon (Billing & Reporting System) | April 2020 April 2022
- Architected and developed a billing and reporting system, including infrastructure setup for Jest, Husky, ESLint, Prettier, i18n, and proxy configurations.
- Managed Angular upgrades from version 9 to 12 and optimized performance using New Relic.
- Technologies: Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, NgRx, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Node.js, Jest, RESTful APIs, AWS.
- Client: Marriott (Leisure Search Project) | March 2019 April 2020
- Led the development and optimization of Marriott's leisure search platform using a proprietary JavaScript framework.
- Managed a team of six members, with a focus on performance and accessibility.
- Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, jQuery, Handlebars, Node.js, Express, HTML5, CSS3.

GlobalLogic | Senior Software Developer | March 2018 - March 2019

- Client: NewsCycle (CRM Application)
- Developed a responsive CRM system under Agile methodology to manage user records and media ad bookings.
- Technologies: AngularJS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, RESTful APIs.

Accenture | Application Development Analyst | July 2015 - February 2018

- Client: T-Mobile (Rebellion 2.0) | July 2016 February 2018
- Developed a responsive website in an Agile environment, contributing to multiple modules including analytics for user activity tracking.
- Technologies: Angular 2/4/6, TypeScript, RxJS, NgRx, Bootstrap, Angular Material, HTML5, CSS3, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Protractor, RESTful APIs.
- Client: T-Mobile (Rebellion 1.0) | July 2015 February 2016
- Migrated applications from AngularJS to Angular 2/4 with added features and performance enhancements.
- Technologies: AngularJS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Less, Bootstrap, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Protractor, RESTful APIs.

Education

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) in Computer Science Engineering - 2010-2014 (8.5 CGPA)

Achievements & Recognitions

Received Client Excellence Award for delivery of complex modules.

Apex Award winner at Accenture for proactive contributions to high-impact projects.

Multiple monetary awards for consistent high performance at Accenture.

Led and mentored a team of six engineers, including onboarding and technical training.

Conducted code reviews and implemented comprehensive unit tests to ensure maintainable and high-quality code.

Successfully transitioned legacy architecture to micro frontend, improving scalability and maintainability.

Actively participated in hiring by conducting technical interviews and mentoring new team members. Improved application performance significantly, enhancing speed and user experience.